Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpat.
I am an MBA in Finance and the founder of Family First
Financial Services. I have been
working in the corporate sector for 13 years.
Today I am presenting to you the
top Yuli Plus
term life insurance policies from life insurance companies. Very few
companies have this type of
product, so I am
taking the top three plans from the top three companies: ICICI's
Protect & Gain AC's Smart
Protect Plan, and TA Life
Insurance's Param Rakshak 3 plan.
I have compared all three plans.
In all three plans, you will get a natural life cover of 50 lakhs, an
accidental
insurance cover of 50 lakhs, and a
permanent disability cover of 50 lakhs.
That is, if you die naturally, you will get 50 lakhs. If you die
accidentally, you will get ₹1 crore. If you do
not die in an accident but develop
disabilities, you will get ₹1 lakh. If
nothing happens to you and you survive the entire policy term, then on a
market basis, you will get a
fund value return of 50 lakhs or more.
You can avail good returns here.  You can take it by paying a premium of up to ₹ lakh.
Your maturity in all three policies will be tax free.
You will get tax benefit in the Income Tax section ATC.
Now, in this plan, I am
trying to explain in this video that
which plans can you take even if your income is low.
Which
plan will you get if your education is low? What will be the income and education
criteria?
Which plan will be good if you are a smoker or a non-smoker?
Whose fund value will be higher and whose
premium will be lower. If I
take insurance cover of 1 crore instead of 50 lakhs, will
I get a discount? If I get it,
which company will give it? I have explained all this in details. Let me
tell you that
in ADFC Life Insurance, there is
no education criteria.
You can take the policy even if you have an income of ₹ lakh.
In ICICI Protect and Gain, you should have an income of ₹ lakh
and should be 12th pass.
And in TA AI's Param Rakshak 3, there is
no education criterion but there is an
income criteria of 3 lakhs. So first of all, income
and  You should check the action criteria and
buy a policy accordingly. Secondly, when your
premium is coming low, then
definitely check the fund value, which one has higher fund value, by
how much percentage is it higher,
how much gap is there in the premium, you can check that and
accordingly you can purchase the policy.
Thirdly, in all these three policies, you will
get the option of partial withdrawal. After 5 years,
if you need to withdraw money,
you can withdraw it, you can do a partial withdrawal
and your insurance cover will continue
and you will get returns on the remaining fund value as per the market. You will get
four to 10-15
funds to invest in. You
can invest in different funds like equity, debt or balance fund. In this way,
you can also take advantage of switching. If the
market is going up, you can go to equity, if the
market is going down, you can go to debt fund or
balance fund. So,
you will get free of cost switching. So, here
you have tax benefit, there is an option of partial withdrawal. If
you are a non-smoker, smoker
You can also see market base returns on the rate
and three types of insurance are given to you.
Watch the full video in details. If you
like the video, then
like, share and subscribe to my YouTube2 Triple FS
and share this video with as many people as possible
so that they can also do good
financial planning. See, I have
mentioned all the premium rates and
what premium will be charged on which age. Here you will get
normal cover of 50 lakhs,
accidental cover of 50 lakhs, permanent disability cover of 50 lakhs.
You will have to
pay premium for only 10 years. If the
policy term is of 40 years or 80 years or 30 years, your
premium will be charged accordingly. Suppose a person of 25 years
and is a non-smoker,
he has to pay premium of 872 for 10 years. He will
get fund value of 4419733 for 40 years.
If the policy term is 40, then the premium remains the same even at the age of 30, that is,
your premium will remain the same.  If
any person between 25 to 40 years of age purchases
ICICI's Protect and Gain policy and
is a non-smoker, then the
premium will be ₹872, which is ₹
50 lakh accidental cover and ₹
0000 normal insurance for disability cover,
and you can see the fund value in front of it.
But the thing to notice is
what benefit you will get from this table is that you will know
that you should purchase the policy before your birthday.
Suppose if you are 40 years old
then you are getting it for ₹64000, but as soon as
your birthday passes and you turn 41, then
your premium will directly increase from ₹50000 to ₹
872. So if you do
not want to pay a higher premium then you will have to keep in mind
that you have to take the policy on time.
Between 48 to 45 your premium will remain the same.
As soon as your age reaches 46 the premium will
directly increase to ₹181. In this way at the age of 51 the
premium will be ₹63000.  It will happen but
if you can afford it then you will
not suffer much loss because for example here the
premium is Rs 64000/- 11000 then the fund
value is also increasing from Rs 34 lakh to Rs 1 crore 3
lakh so your premium is increasing from Rs
50000 to Rs 77, your premium is increasing
from Rs 50000 to Rs 78000 which is
about Rs 200 your fund value is increasing
so if you can afford the premium then you
can take the benefit of fund value
but if you want that insurance is your
main focus then it will be beneficial
for you to take the policy early even by going for a lower premium.
Now if we look at ICICI's Protect and
Gain, if we compare non-smoker vs smoker, if there is
a person who is a smoker and a
non-smoker, both of them take the policy at the
same age, then will there be any difference between them, suppose if a
person is a 25 year old non-smoker then the
premium is Rs 67000 but if he smokes
then the premium is Rs 86000  A 30 year old
person is getting it for Rs 64000. If
you see the premium here at Rs 86000, then the premium is going to be the same till 40 years, that is,
you have to pay an extra premium of Rs 2429. If you have to pay an
extra premium at Rs 33, then
your fund value will increase due to smoking. Your
fund value also increases at Rs 54, Rs 70, Rs 96.
So if
you can afford a higher premium
because you are getting the benefit of the fund value,
but you want to
get it at a cheaper rate or it will be better if you get it at a cheaper rate, then
this one will be better for you. For a non-
smoker, it is Rs 64000 or
your fund value is
also increasing in the same way as the amount invested. Look here, in 41 cases,
if you buy a policy for Rs 11000 for a non-smoker,
the same smoker may have to
pay Rs 157000. So, smoking can
also make a big difference to you. Now,
in comparison, see the
Protect and Gain of ICICI Presence Life Insurance and
HDFC Life Insurance.
If we compare Smart Protect and Gain with the non-
smoker rate, what will be the rate? If you notice from here, then from
25 to 40 years, the semi-
premium is coming and here you notice
36 37 38 39 40, here the premium of HDFC is
coming higher, there is a difference of about ₹1,600 in
premium, HDFC is
cheaper than ICIC, so
you will see a difference in the fund value as well, there will be a
difference of about 20.2 lakh in the fund value,
which is from 8 to 60 percent, so now you have to
see whether you have to
purchase the policy as per the premium or you have to
purchase the policy as per the fund value, so here
separately,
here in 41 percent, the premium is 114,000, so the
fund value is 1 crore 3 lakh, here the
premium is 109,000, so the fund
value is 94,000, so see here there is a difference of 5 percent
premium, so there is a difference of 8 percent in the fund value
So at the age of 41, there is
not much major difference in which policy you can purchase from both the companies as per your priority. At the age of 46
also there is not much major difference, there is a
difference of 5% which is not a big deal
but yes between 36 to 40 there is
definitely a huge difference in premium and fund value,
so you
can see and select as per your convenience. If we talk about
someone who consumes smoking tobacco, then what will be the
difference in fund value or
premium of
ICICI and ADAC. For example, if a
40 year old person purchases a policy from ICICI, he will pay a
premium of ₹86000. In ADAC, he will pay a premium of ₹81 and will
give you ₹5000000 percent more. So now you
can see it this way also. Now first of all,
if you are a smoker, if you are 25 years old
or 30 years old or 35 years old, then
for you  HDFC is getting much cheaper, the
premium is getting much cheaper, at 43 the
premium is getting cheaper, there
is definitely a difference of 58 per cent in the fund value but there
is a difference of 43 per cent in the premium as well, the
difference in the fund value is so much
because your money grows with the power of compounding,
power of compounding is a very
good feature, it is a
very
good tool to make a lot of money, power of compounding is simple
interest,
so you can compare here also,
suppose look at the age of 40 to 45,
where the premium of Rs 57000 will be charged, a premium of Rs
440000 will be
saved, but yes there will be a
difference of around Rs 50 lakh in merit also, so
you can see here whether you have to pay less premium or not,
here one thing to notice is that at the
age of 51 years, where the age of 50 years,
see if the premium is Rs 1 lakh or Rs
370000, then the premium of Rs 1 lakh will
come as soon as the premium is charged.  Maturity becomes taxable,
so you should take care that your premium does
not go above Rs 8 lakh so that
whatever crores of rupees are coming on your maturity,
it should come tax free.
Now let's see the comparison on non-smoker rate
ICICI Protect & GUN
vs ADFC Smart Protect vs
Tata A Param Rakshak 3.
At the age of 25, the premium is Rs 64,000.
ICICI's premium is Rs 600,000
from SDF, so Tata is charging only Rs 39,000,
approximately Rs 242,000 less premium,
but Tata's fund value
is less than Rs 10 lakh and ICICI STFC's
premium fund value is more than Rs 40 lakh, that is,
four times more than Tata. Now I
want to see the premium here that
you need Rs 20,000 less premium and
my main focus is insurance, then you should
purchase Tata's Param Rakshak. If you feel
that no, I need a better return along with the insurance cover and
fund value, then
you can buy ADFC or
ICICI.  You can select any plan,
for example, at the age of 40,
see, ICICI is charging a premium of Rs. 000,
ADFC is charging a premium of Rs. 81000,
TA is also charging a premium of Rs. 81000,
but the fund value of TA is Rs. 34000, that
of ADFC is Rs. 60 lakh and that of ICICI is Rs. 34 lakh. So,
if you
compare ICICI and Tata, there is a
difference of Rs. 20000 in premium, but there is
almost no difference in the fund value. But if you
compare ADFC and Tata, there
is no difference in the premium, but there is a
huge difference of around Rs. 24 lakh.
You can get a higher maturity of Rs. 24 to 26 lakh. So,
you also have to see
where you are getting more returns and
where you have to pay less premium.
How is your affordability or
what is your objective? You
can make a purchase by comparing with that. For example,
here you can notice that there are plans of Rs. 46 lakh or Rs.
45 lakh.  But see if the fund value is one crore or
6 lakh or 63 lakh, if the fund
value is one crore 63 lakh then there is a
huge difference, this is probably
because of the policy term given as 30 years, the
rest of the policy term is 40, there cannot be any difference than this, the
policy term is 40 only, but it is 40 only, please see 30 or 40,
finally let us see, have you
seen the smoker rate comparison,
if you do a smoker rate of all the three companies, then here at a
rate of 40,
HDFC is charging the lowest premium in the smoker rate and
their fund value is also good at 60 lakh,
now in Tata our premium is 11000,
their maturity is only 62, in ICICI the
premium is 157, at a rate of 41 ADFC
is giving a much cheaper premium, despite Tata taking a premium of one, the
fund value is less than ADFC
and the premium is also higher, if you
look at a rate of 50, ICICI is
charging 252000, so go for 175 HDFC
Tata is taking Rs 37000, so this also matters a lot.
Now finally let me tell you
that if you wait for a longer time instead of Rs 50 lakh,
suppose you take an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore, then
what benefit will you get
in the fund value or in the premium. For example,
look at ICICI, at the age of 25, the
premium is Rs 67000. If you take Rs 50 lakh for Rs 1 crore, then
its exact double becomes Rs 129000.
In Rs 40 case also, Rs 64 becomes Rs 29. In Rs 41 case, Rs
11000 becomes Rs 29000. That means, if you get Rs
50 lakh to Rs 1 crore, then
ICICI is
not giving you any kind of rebate.
Even if you go to Tata's Param Rakshak, you
get a cover of Rs 50 lakh for Rs 39, so its double
becomes Rs 78000. In Rs 1 crore, suppose it is Rs 40,
then its double becomes Rs 162. So here also
you will not see any difference in the premium
in the fund value, definitely.  It will
appear higher due to the power of compounding but there
is no rebate in the premium but if you
look at the HDFC
plan, for example, if you notice here that at age 36
you are getting a premium of Rs 81000 for Rs 50
lakh, then for Rs 1 crore, Rs 81 is
not doubling to Rs 162, it is directly getting Rs 120000,
so here you are getting a difference,
if your age is from 36 to 37, 38, 39 and 40, then it will be
better for you to take a sum of Rs 1 crore in HDFC
from the premium point of view, similarly here you see, at the
age of 41, 46 also it is not doubling directly, there is a
difference on this too, so
if you look at everywhere, if
you are taking a cover of Rs 1 crore instead of Rs 50 lakh in HDFC, then
you get a rebate in the premium, I have
already told you in the education and income criteria
that in ICICI you should be 12th pass,
income proof of Rs 3 lakh will be required,
in HDFC Rs 2 lakh  Income education
criteria There is no education criteria in Tata's Param Rakshak
and you will be charged an income of 3 lakhs.
Now let me explain to you the illustration of ICICI's Protect and
Gain. For
example, there is a person whose
age
is 37. You will see that his age is 37 years old
and he is paying premium for 10 years and
taking a policy term of 40 years.
Natural cover of Rs. 1 crore. The name of the plan is ICC
Protect and Gain. And he is a non-smoker, so
his premium will be Rs. 1 lakh. For basic
accidental death benefit you will get Rs. 000 and
for accidental death and disability benefit you will get Rs.
10000. So the premium will be Rs. 12000 and
with GST your
premium will be Rs. 9742 for 10 years. Now
you will see here you will see the table at 4 and at 8.
And I will try to explain to you. From
here, from Part B, you will see
that the customer is paying a premium of Rs. 1 lakh
because the rider premium  So the
investment does not happen, in the first year their
premium allocation charges of Rs. 000 are levied, so a
good thing is that after 10 years
you will get double the premium allocation, if
you look at the column you will see return of premium allocation,
in this you are
getting a refund of Rs. 24000 after 10 years, next year premium
allocation of Rs. 5000 is being deducted, then Rs. 10000 is being refunded to you,
now you will see the major charge of Rs. 14820, in
this way
mortality charges are also doubled after two years, Rs.
14820 is doubled to Rs. 2641,
so you will get return of premium as well as return of
mortality charges and the big
thing is that you are getting double the amount back and when
after 25 years you will get triple the amount back,
like at 26 years you will see mortality
charges of Rs.
15365 are being returned, if you see this, then the
total charges which have been deducted for 16 years, you are getting
three times of Rs. 000, here you are
getting Rs. 158000  So, that means after 25 years,
you are getting back three times the mortality, so
you are getting back the charges that are levied.
Secondly,
like on age, a table is made on government rules 4 and 8,
but because the company is
refunding the charges and is also giving a maturity booster,
you get a maturity booster at the
end of the policy, it is of Rs
8872,
you get a maturity booster at 20% of the average fund value of the last three years.
Maturity booster is
not available in any company. In ADFC, you
get back the FMC charges or you do
not get the FMC charges back, but you
get the booster back as a booster,
whereas in Tata, there is neither a booster nor an FMC
charges fund. Now you will see here that
because of all these returns,
your actual return is 9.08 and the
market based return can be even better.
When you invest in 40 years, the
Indian market will be very good,
so you are going to get market based returns,
so you will see here
Maturity 84 la 11970 E means a
person who purchased the policy at the age of 37,
two-three things can happen in his life,
either if
nothing happens to him then he will get a maturity of 84 lakhs,
if he dies a natural death then he will
get ₹ crore, if he dies in an accident
then he will get 1 to 2 crores,
if he does
not die but even if he becomes disabled then also
he will get one crore rupees, so in this way
he also has the benefit of insurance cover
and even if nothing happens then he is getting a good
maturity cover, you can see, so
finally if I summarize this video then all the
three plans are good because if
you go for normal term insurance then most of the companies ask you to be a graduate,
that your education should be graduate
or your income should be 5 lakhs or more,
but all these three plans are
providing you insurance cover for income less than 5 lakhs and less education, they are also
giving accidental cover along with
disabilities  We are giving benefits as well as
market based returns. You are also
getting the benefit of Income Tax Section ATC
and your upcoming maturity is
also tax free. You are also getting the opportunity to invest from one fund to another
and if required,
you are also getting the facility to withdraw money without taking a loan.
In all the three plans, you
can purchase any plan as per your requirement.
If you want to purchase a policy from me, then
contact me on 9094 3412. My
name is Anil Rajpat and my
customers get benefited, that is, you will get
benefited. Compare, save money and
get more fun value. Jai
Hind.